Frank Sully papers
UCLA Library Special Collections
Frank Sully papers
circa 1920s – circa 1970s
2249
UCLA Library Special Collections
1.0 linear ft. (1 box and 1 flat box)
Frank Sully started his acting career in 1929 and appeared on stage, film and television. The collection consists of a small amount of scripts, photographs, biographical information, clippings, and contracts related to Sully’s career.
Sully, Frank, 1908-1975
Restrictions on Access
COLLECTION STORED OFF-SITE AT SRLF: Open for research. Advance notice required for access. Contact the UCLA Library Special Collections Reference Desk for paging information.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Mikell Ann Kemper, 2014.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 7797453
Biography/History
Frank Sullivan, professionally known as Frank Sully and as Sully, was born in 1908 in St. Louis, Missouri. He began his career in Vaudeville in 1929. His stage work included Whoopee (1933), Midsummer Night’s Dream (1934) and Kiss Me, Kate (1955). During World War II, Sully performed in U.S.O. Camp Shows. Much of his professional work was concentrated in film and television where he was frequently cast as folksy or villainous characters. In 1940, Frank Sully starred in the film adaption of Grapes of Wrath. Other film appearances include Let’s Go Collegiate (1941), Bye Bye Birdie (1963), and Funny Girl (1968), among others. His many television credits include The Beverly Hillbillies, Colt .45, and The Virginian. He died December 17, 1975 in Woodland Hills, California.
Scope and Content
The collection consists of materials related to the career of actor Frank Sully. Included are a small amount of scripts, photographs, clippings, residual payment stubs, contracts, and biographical information. The two scripts represent the motion pictures The Grapes of Wrath and Funny Girl. The photographs represent motion picture and television projects, many of which are not identified, and headshots of Sully. Additionally, there are a small number of professional photographs of his first wife and performer Gladys Edris Slycott (also known as Edris Purcell) and autographed photographs of performers. Residual stubs document his work at Columbia Pictures, Universal, and Warner Bros.
Organization and Arrangement
The collection is organized in loose alphabetical order by file title.
Container List
- Biographical Information., undated. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Residuals., 1966-1976. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Clippings., circa 1940s and 1972. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Contracts., 1952 and 1967. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Funny Girl - script, production, information, still and lobby card., circa 1967. (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Grapes of Wrath (The) - script., 5 Aug 1939. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Kiss Me, Kate - rehearsal schedule and clipping., 1955. (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Midsummer Night's Dream (A) - program and published playscript., circa 1934.
- U.S.O Appearance - schedule., 29 Mar 1944. (Box 1, Folder 9)
- photographs of Gladys Edris Sylcott (AKA Edris Purcell) - (33 items)., undated. (Box 2, Folder 1)
- photographs of performers signed (mostly to Sully) (10 items)., undated. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  Scope and Content
  James Cagney, Ken Curtis, Jimmy Durante, Bob Hope, Gene Kelly, Arthur Lake, Jack Oakie, and Roy Rogers with others.
- Photographs of Sully (headshots) (40 items)., undated. (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Photographs of Sully with Others Undentified Appearances (19 items)., no date. (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Unidentified motion picture - stills (9 items)., no date. (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Unidentified title - stills (15 originals and 1 facsimile)., no date. (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Unidentified motion picture - stills (4 items)., no date. (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Boogie Man Will Get You - stills (2 items)., no date. (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Bye Bye Birdie - stills (2 originals and 1 facsimile)., no date. (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Down Among The Sheltering Palms (AKA Friendly Island) - stills (2 items)., no date. (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Honeymoon Pilot - stills (2 items)., no date. (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Laugh Your Blues Away - stills (2 items)., no date. (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Let's Go Collegiate - stills (11 originals and 2 facsimiles)., no date. (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Man in the Saddle - still., no date. (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Man's World (A) - stills (13 items)., no date. (Box 2, Folder 14)
- More The Merrier (The) - still., no date. (Box 2, Folder 15)
- There's Something About A Soldier - stills (3 items)., no date. (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Whoopee - still and credits., no date. (Box 2, Folder 17)